<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stephen J Eglen</title>
    <link>http://sje30.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stephen J Eglen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2016 ~ Stephen J Eglen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://sje30.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why paperpile?</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/why-paperpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/why-paperpile/</guid>
      <description>Why is paperpile useful?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief introduction to reproducible research and open science</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/brief-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/brief-open/</guid>
      <description>[The following was written for the British Neuroscience Association]
A brief introduction to reproducible research and open science
At first glance, it might seem odd that you would need to prefix the term &amp;ldquo;research&amp;rdquo; with the qualifier &amp;ldquo;reproducible&amp;rdquo;. Surely, once you have a paper in your hands, you have all the details in front of you to reproduce someone else&amp;rsquo;s work? That&amp;rsquo;s certainly the theory when writing the paper, but it&amp;rsquo;s often not the practice&amp;hellip; Since 2004 we&amp;rsquo;ve set a problem for our masters students to reproduce key results from a paper within computational biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An interactive introduction to computational neuroscience</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/neuro-binder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/neuro-binder/</guid>
      <description>For a few years I&amp;rsquo;ve given a workshop, a two hour introduction to computational neuroscience, for masters students. This has covered the Hodgkin-Huxley model of action potential generation, reduced models, and simple small-networks. Most of the content was previously matlab code, provided by other researchers, most notably Hugh Wilson and Eugene Izhikevich.
Over the last few months, we (mostly Derek Fulton and Paraskevi Mylona) have converted this matlab code to the Julia programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards standard practice for sharing of code and data in neuroscience</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/code-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/code-sharing/</guid>
      <description>Scientists are increasingly dependent on computational techniques to analyse large volumes of data. These computational methods are often tailored to the particular analysis in mind, and as such are valuable research outputs. Furthermore, unlike experimental techniques, computational methods can be easily shared. However, at least in neuroscience, computational methods are not routinely shared upon publication of associated manuscripts.
To improve this situation, we have worked with the editors of Nature Neuroscience to establish a pilot code review project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/latex2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 14:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/latex2016/</guid>
      <description>Every year I give a one-hour lecture introducting LaTeX to mathematics undergraduates and Masters students. After the lecture, I normally host a lab session for students to work through some material.
Slides The slides for the talk are, of-course, written in LaTeX using the Beamer package. The source code for the files are available on github. (New for 2016 is that I&amp;rsquo;ve switch to the sourcesanspro font.)
Lab material I&amp;rsquo;ve written a short template file for students to adopt when writing their own reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Analysis of Neuroanatomy ebook</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/qan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/qan/</guid>
      <description>On behalf of all the editors, I am pleased to announce the release of our special issue on the Quantitative Analysis of Neuroanatomy. All articles have been published in Frontiers in Neuroanatomy. As of March 2016, all papers are now freely available as an Ebook either in PDF or EPUB format.
The aim of this Research Topic is to examine theoretical and experimental work directed at a detailed and comprehensive quantitative understanding of neuroanatomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBC News</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/link/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 17:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/link/example/</guid>
      <description>1 Content of your comment on external link goes here.
hello</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>maps2015 workshop</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/maps2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 17:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/maps2015/</guid>
      <description>On 7-9 December 2015, we hosted maps2015 in Strasbourg, France. The primary aim of the meeting was to bring together the two communities of theoreticians and experimentalists working on related problems in developmental neurobiology. This was the second meeting that we have hosted on this topic, following on from maps2014.org in Edinburgh. This year the programme took a slightly wider scope: although most talks were related to the development and order in brain maps, we also had several interesting talks including mouse and zebrafish behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 14:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/research/</guid>
      <description> Retinal waves Analysis of neural spike trains Topographic map formation Reproducible research Open access </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 14:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/first/</guid>
      <description>Content of the file goes here
here is a very long para here is a very long para here is a very long para here is a very long para here is a very long para here is a very long para here is a very long para
 this is a quote
 verbatim verbatim     Right Left Center     Long Content To Spread Out the Width Of the Table To See Alignment   Right Left Center   a b c    s = &amp;quot;this is a very long string that is likely to take a lot of space&amp;quot; x = 10  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/license/</guid>
      <description>hello.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/papers/</guid>
      <description>After each reference, Paper links to papers; Info to further information about that paper, including code and data.
Preprints Cotterill E, Eglen SJ (2018) Burst detection methods. arXiv [q-bioNC] Paper.
Gelfman S, Wang Q, Lu Y-F, Hall D, Bostick C, Dhindsa R, Halvorsen M, Melodi McSweeney K, Cotterill E, Edinburgh T, Petrovski S, Boland MJ, Allen AS, Goldstein DB, Eglen SJ (2018) meaRtools: an R package for the Comprehensive Analysis of Neuronal Networks Recorded on Multi-Electrode Arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here you can find various resources that I have made available to the community. A key principle of our work is that whenever possible, we make our code and data freely available to the community. You can find links to the relevant code/data alongside each paper listed on my publications page.
In addition to those papers, I highlight some key resources below.
IntactEye IntactEye is a program for measuring the location of injection sites in the intact eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephen J Eglen</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description>I am a Reader in Computational Neuroscience in the Department of Applied Mathematics and Theoretical Physics, and member of the Cambridge Computational Biology Institute CCBI. I use computational techniques to investigate development of the nervous system. I am also director of the MPhil in Computational Biology. Fellow of Magdalene College.
orcid.org/0000-0001-8607-8025
Office hour I normally have an office hour during term time. My office hour in Michaelmas term is Monday 1-2pm in G0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/talks/</guid>
      <description>Here are some slides for talks I have given recently. (Some Keynote slides are missing.)
2017 On a role for competition (and sharing) in computational neuroscience BNDU Science Day, Oxford.
Encouraging code and data sharing in neuroscience RDM meeting, Cambridge.
Encouraging code and data sharing in neuroscience CNS 2017 Workshops, Antwerp.
Detecting pairwise correlations in high-density recordings: open science in action CNS 2017 Workshops, Antwerp.
Encouraging code sharing in academia, Research software management, sharing and sustainability workshop, Cambridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I lecture on several courses in the University. In 2015&amp;ndash;16 these are:
 Computaional Neuroscience Scientific Programming in R Part II Neuroscience (N1: Developmental Neuroscience)   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>