<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Stephen J Eglen</title>
    <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Stephen J Eglen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2016 ~ Stephen J Eglen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 14:49:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://sje30.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 14:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/research/</guid>
      <description> Retinal waves Analysis of neural spike trains Topographic map formation Reproducible research Open access </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/license/</guid>
      <description>hello.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/papers/</guid>
      <description>After each reference, Paper links to papers; Info to further information about that paper, including code and data.
Preprints Cotterill E, Eglen SJ (2018) Burst detection methods. arXiv [q-bioNC] Paper.
Gelfman S, Wang Q, Lu Y-F, Hall D, Bostick C, Dhindsa R, Halvorsen M, Melodi McSweeney K, Cotterill E, Edinburgh T, Petrovski S, Boland MJ, Allen AS, Goldstein DB, Eglen SJ (2018) meaRtools: an R package for the Comprehensive Analysis of Neuronal Networks Recorded on Multi-Electrode Arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here you can find various resources that I have made available to the community. A key principle of our work is that whenever possible, we make our code and data freely available to the community. You can find links to the relevant code/data alongside each paper listed on my publications page.
In addition to those papers, I highlight some key resources below.
IntactEye IntactEye is a program for measuring the location of injection sites in the intact eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/talks/</guid>
      <description>Here are some slides for talks I have given recently. (Some Keynote slides are missing.)
2017 On a role for competition (and sharing) in computational neuroscience BNDU Science Day, Oxford.
Encouraging code and data sharing in neuroscience RDM meeting, Cambridge.
Encouraging code and data sharing in neuroscience CNS 2017 Workshops, Antwerp.
Detecting pairwise correlations in high-density recordings: open science in action CNS 2017 Workshops, Antwerp.
Encouraging code sharing in academia, Research software management, sharing and sustainability workshop, Cambridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://sje30.github.io/page/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sje30.github.io/page/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I lecture on several courses in the University. In 2015&amp;ndash;16 these are:
 Computaional Neuroscience Scientific Programming in R Part II Neuroscience (N1: Developmental Neuroscience)   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>