<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Stephen J Eglen</title>
    <link>http://sje30.github.io/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Stephen J Eglen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://sje30.github.io/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Why paperpile?</title>
            <link>http://sje30.github.io/post/why-paperpile/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://sje30.github.io/post/why-paperpile/</guid>
            <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://paperpile.com&#34;&gt;Paperpile&lt;/a&gt; is a web application to manage your academic
PDFs and other references.  There is a snappy 2 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; minute video that
shows it in action:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/0r80ecyGlCw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When visiting a web page containing a paper (e.g. from a journal web
page), you can click on the Paperpile button in your browser to
download the paper and its metadata.  It also adds Paperpile import
buttons on sites like &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.google.co.uk&#34;&gt;Google
Scholar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://arxiv.org&#34;&gt;arXiv&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://pubmed.gov&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; to easily import data.  Below
is partial output from arXiv &amp;ndash; at the end of each &lt;em&gt;Subjects&lt;/em&gt;
line you should see the &amp;ldquo;+ Paperpile&amp;rdquo; button that you can click to add
the article to your collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sje30.github.io/img/arxiv-paperpile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Paperpile buttons on arXiv&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the reasons I like paperpile; I also mention some
current limitations at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;bibtex-support:7227b2bf899686212fedfb82b162d860&#34;&gt;BibTeX support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paperpile has first class support for BibTeX references.  If you use
LaTeX, you will never need to hand-write a BibTeX reference again.
Here is an example BibTeX reference as formatted by Paperpile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;

@ARTICLE{Damani2011-99e,
  title    = &#34;Age-related alterations in the dynamic behavior of microglia&#34;,
  author   = &#34;Damani, Mausam R and Zhao, Lian and Fontainhas, Aurora M and
              Amaral, Juan and Fariss, Robert N and Wong, Wai T&#34;,
  abstract = &#34;Microglia, the primary resident immune cells of the central
              nervous system (CNS), exhibit dynamic behavior involving rapid
              process motility and cellular migration that is thought to
              underlie key functions of immune surveillance and tissue repair.
              Although age-related changes in microglial activation have been
              ... abstract truncated for brevity ...
              behavior at rest and following injury reveal an age-dependent
              dysregulation of immune response in the CNS that may illuminate
              microglial contributions to age-related neuroinflammatory
              degeneration.&#34;,
  journal  = &#34;Aging Cell&#34;,
  volume   =  10,
  number   =  2,
  pages    = &#34;263--276&#34;,
  month    =  apr,
  year     =  2011,
  issn     = &#34;1474-9718&#34;,
  pmid     = &#34;21108733&#34;,
  doi      = &#34;10.1111/j.1474-9726.2010.00660.x&#34;,
  pmc      = &#34;PMC3056927&#34;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My workflow is that I create a Paperpile tag for each paper that I&amp;rsquo;m
writing, and mark the papers I&amp;rsquo;m referencing with that tag.  I can
then easily select all the papers with that tag, and export all those
references as BibTeX entries, and copy them into my BibTeX file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the tag used for a BibTeX reference is automatically
generated, e.g. &lt;em&gt;Damani2011-99e&lt;/em&gt; above.  The &lt;em&gt;-99e&lt;/em&gt; suffix is a
hashcode, which I used to find a bit irritating as you can&amp;rsquo;t remember
them, but now I simply use my latex editor (Emacs) to look up the
BibTeX keys anyway.  If you prefer your own BibTeX tags, you can edit
the metadata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not a BibTeX user, then you might find the Google Docs
plugin useful for writing papers with references.  (See below for Word
users&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sharing-papers-with-others-is-easy:7227b2bf899686212fedfb82b162d860&#34;&gt;Sharing papers with others is easy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before using Paperpile, if I wanted to share a paper with a colleague,
I&amp;rsquo;d email it to them.  Works fine, but then your inbox gets clogged up
with lots of emails containing large PDF attachments.  Paperpile
allows you to share links to papers.  E.g. here is a link for the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://paperpile.com/app/p/cd0a745f-a4ff-0cb7-b457-0a2a3e7b309e&#34;&gt;Damani et
al. paper&lt;/a&gt;.
Furthemore, this extends to sharing multiple papers at once.  For
example, if you organise papers into folders, you can freely share the
PDFs in a folder by sharing the link to that folder.  Here is an
example of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://paperpile.com/shared/toXwJV&#34;&gt;folder link&lt;/a&gt; that I
created to accompany a tutorial.  This is an excellent resource for
sharing papers.  You must however actively create a link to share your
papers &amp;ndash; by default, everything is private to your account.  Papers
can be shared with named individuals or to anyone who has the
corresponding link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;it-tidies-your-pdf-collection:7227b2bf899686212fedfb82b162d860&#34;&gt;It tidies your pdf collection&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a large collection of PDFs living in some folder on your
laptop, you can import them directly into Paperpile.  It does a very
good job at extracting the metadata from PDFs (but of course this is
dependent on the quality of the PDF).  Your PDFs live on Google drive
and organises them into folders, one per letter of the alphabet,
such as &lt;strong&gt;Google Drive / Paperpile / AllPapers / D / Damani et al. 2011 -
Age-related alterations in the dynamic behaviour of microglia.pdf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, even if nothing else you can get your PDFs reorganized.  (To see
this google drive on your laptop, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.uk/drive/&#34;&gt;Google
Drive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;it-is-very-slick-at-what-it-does:7227b2bf899686212fedfb82b162d860&#34;&gt;It is very slick at what it does&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other reference managers are available, e.g. zotero, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found
paperpile to be incredibly efficient at organising papers.  The
interface has been designed with care.  The Paperpile team are
efficient at answering queries, and there is a useful
&lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.paperpile.com&#34;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt; for discussions and requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-not-paperpile:7227b2bf899686212fedfb82b162d860&#34;&gt;Why not paperpile?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paperpile isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect (yet).  Some reasons that you may need to
consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It does not yet have a Word plugin, so you can&amp;rsquo;t seamlessly write
manuscripts in Word and include references from paperpile.  I
believe there is a Word plug-in coming soon though, which hopefully
will look something like the Google docs plugin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You must use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.uk/chrome/&#34;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;
web browser to access Paperpile.  Support for android and ipad
devices are also in the works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cost.  Paperpile costs about $3/month, which although not
expensive, is more than some of the competition:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://zotero.org&#34;&gt;zotero&lt;/a&gt; and Mendeley are free.  Individuals can
get a free one-month trial to evaluate it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You need to be online to use it.  (In this case I recommed you use
Google Drive to ensure you have the Paperpile folder synced to your
laptop so that you can always read your papers.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary:7227b2bf899686212fedfb82b162d860&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paperpile is an excellent tool for managing your academic references.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-cambridge-readers:7227b2bf899686212fedfb82b162d860&#34;&gt;For Cambridge readers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maths.cam.ac.uk&#34;&gt;Maths faculty&lt;/a&gt; at the University of
Cambridge are trialing a site license for a year to assess its
utility.  We would encourage other departments around Cambridge to
consider joining in.  Please contact &lt;a href=&#34;http://sje30.github.io&#34;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; for
further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--  LocalWords:  Paperpile
 --&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
